{"questions": [{"question": "Which one is the capital of Morocco?", "category": "Geography", "difficulty": "easy", "points": 10.0, "options": ["Fes", "Marrakech", "Rabat", "Casablanca"], "correctOption": 2}, {"question": "The four main divisions of philosophy are metaphysics, epistomology, axiology and ...", "category": "Philosophy", "difficulty": "medium", "points": 20.0, "options": ["Bioethics", "Logic", "Categorical logic", "Aesthetics"], "correctOption": 1}, {"question": "Which river flows through Egypt?", "category": "Geography", "difficulty": "easy", "points": 10.0, "options": ["Nile", "Volga", "Amazon", "Rhine"], "correctOption": 0}, {"question": "What is the brain of the computer?", "category": "Computer Science", "difficulty": "easy", "points": 10.0, "options": ["Hard drive", "CPU", "Keyboard", "Monitor"], "correctOption": 1}, {"question": "What does RAM stand for?", "category": "Computer Science", "difficulty": "medium", "points": 20.0, "options": ["Random allocation memory", "Read access memory", "Run access memory", "Random access memory"], "correctOption": 3}, {"question": "Which was the name of Aphrodite Child's first album?", "category": "Music", "difficulty": "hard", "points": 30.0, "options": ["End Of The World", "666", "Reflection", "It's Five O'Clock"], "correctOption": 0}, {"question": "What year did Yes release their debut album?", "category": "Music", "difficulty": "medium", "points": 20.0, "options": ["1969", "1971", "1973", "1974"], "correctOption": 0}, {"question": "Which letter is silent in the word 'solemn'?", "category": "Linguistics", "difficulty": "medium", "points": 20.0, "options": ["n", "m", "s", "l"], "correctOption": 0}, {"question": "We are at about 4000 BC, looking for the original speakers of Indo-European. What area would be the best place to look?", "category": "Linguistics", "difficulty": "medium", "points": 20.0, "options": ["Iberian Peninsula", "Northern India", "Eurasian steppes", "Anatolian plateau"], "correctOption": 2}, {"question": "Which of these former languages in Italy is not considered to be an Indo-European language?", "category": "Linguistics", "difficulty": "hard", "points": 30.0, "options": ["South Picene", "Etruscan", "Oscan", "Umbrian"], "correctOption": 1}, {"question": "Which of those is not an album by Premiata Forneria Marconi?", "category": "Music", "difficulty": "hard", "points": 30.0, "options": ["Storia di un minuto", "Io sono nato libero", "L'isola di niente", "Per un amico"], "correctOption": 1}, {"question": "In which modern-day country did the Inca Empire exist?", "category": "History", "difficulty": "easy", "points": 10.0, "options": ["Guatemala", "Mexico", "Venezuela", "Peru"], "correctOption": 3}, {"question": "Which author wrote 'Catch-22' ?", "category": "Literature", "difficulty": "medium", "points": 20.0, "options": ["Vladimir Nabokov", "Kurt Vonnegut", "Joseph Heller", "Cassandra Clare"], "correctOption": 2}, {"question": "Which British band released the album 'Parachutes' ?", "category": "Music", "difficulty": "medium", "points": 20.0, "options": ["Coldplay", "Radiohead", "Pulp", "Oasis"], "correctOption": 0}, {"question": "Tegucigalpa is the capital city of which country?", "category": "Geography", "difficulty": "medium", "points": 20.0, "options": ["Guatemala", "Honduras", "Nicaragua", "El Salvador"], "correctOption": 1}, {"question": "When was the partition between India and Pakistan?", "category": "History", "difficulty": "easy", "points": 10.0, "options": ["1891", "1763", "1947", "1999"], "correctOption": 2}, {"question": "Which English rock band released the song 'Pinball Wizard' ?", "category": "Music", "difficulty": "easy", "points": 10.0, "options": ["The Who", "Deep Purple", "Led Zeppelin", "The Kinks"], "correctOption": 0}, {"question": "The countries of Belgium, Netherlands, and Luxembourg are together called _______ .", "category": "Geography", "difficulty": "easy", "points": 10.0, "options": ["Benelux", "Luxelneth", "Benengium", "Nethiumberg"], "correctOption": 0}, {"question": "What is the capital of Chad?", "category": "Geography", "difficulty": "easy", "points": 10.0, "options": ["Bangui", "Luanda", "Yaounde", "N'djamena"], "correctOption": 3}, {"question": "Which philosopher famously said 'Man is born free, but is everywhere in chains' ?", "category": "Philosophy", "difficulty": "medium", "points": 20.0, "options": ["Baruch de Spinoza", "Jean-Jacques Rousseau", "Jean-Paul Sartre", "Ludwig Wittgenstein"], "correctOption": 1}, {"question": "Who wrote \"The Great Gatsby\" ?", "category": "Literature", "difficulty": "easy", "points": 10.0, "options": ["Ray Bradbury", "F. Scott Fitzgerald", "Harper Lee", "Joseph Heller"], "correctOption": 1}, {"question": "What did British Honduras change its name to in 1973?", "category": "Geography", "difficulty": "easy", "points": 10.0, "options": ["Jamaica", "Belize", "Guatemala", "Barbados"], "correctOption": 1}, {"question": "Which US state is divided into two parts by a large lake?", "category": "Geography", "difficulty": "medium", "points": 20.0, "options": ["Michigan", "Ohio", "Minnesota", "Wisconsin"], "correctOption": 0}, {"question": "Which English heavy metal band released the album 'The Number of the Beast' ?", "category": "Music", "difficulty": "medium", "points": 20.0, "options": ["Iron Maiden", "Judas Priest", "Mot\u00f6rhead", "Black Sabbath"], "correctOption": 0}, {"question": "Which is a measure of computer performance in intensive calculations?", "category": "Computer Science", "difficulty": "medium", "points": 20.0, "options": ["GIGO", "ECOS", "POSIX", "FLOPS"], "correctOption": 3}, {"question": "When creating a website, what is one of the things, CSS allows you to do?", "category": "Computer Science", "difficulty": "medium", "points": 20.0, "options": ["Adjust font size", "Copy to clipboard", "Attach event listener", "Database queries"], "correctOption": 0}, {"question": "In which sequence get elements closer to each other as it progresses?", "category": "Mathematics", "difficulty": "medium", "points": 20.0, "options": ["Arithmetic sequence", "Fibonacci sequence", "Cauchy sequence", "Mersenne primes"], "correctOption": 2}, {"question": "What is the range of this dataset: {7,9,17,6,8}?", "category": "Mathematics", "difficulty": "easy", "points": 10.0, "options": ["8", "6", "11", "9"], "correctOption": 2}, {"question": "What is the second note of the major G scale?", "category": "Music", "difficulty": "easy", "points": 10.0, "options": ["E", "F#", "C", "A"], "correctOption": 3}, {"question": "What is a common method for training artificial neural networks?", "category": "Computer Science", "difficulty": "medium", "points": 20.0, "options": ["Backpropagation", "Gauss-Jordan elimination", "Hessenberg expansion", "Vertex enumeration"], "correctOption": 0}, {"question": "Which author wrote 'The Lord of the Rings'?", "category": "Literature", "difficulty": "easy", "points": 10.0, "options": ["Philip Pullman", "J. R. R. Tolkien", "G. K. Chesterton", "C. S. Lewis"], "correctOption": 1}, {"question": "Which philosopher famously said 'One cannot step twice in the same river' ?", "category": "Philosophy", "difficulty": "easy", "points": 10.0, "options": ["Ludwig Wittgenstein", "Baruch de Spinoza", "Heraclitus", "Denis Diderot"], "correctOption": 2}, {"question": "If a mathematical function is both -injective and surjective-, it is...", "category": "Mathematics", "difficulty": "medium", "points": 20.0, "options": ["superjective", "perijective", "bijective", "intersubjective"], "correctOption": 2}, {"question": "The Occitan language is spoken in certain parts of Southern ... ?", "category": "Linguistics", "difficulty": "easy", "points": 10.0, "options": ["France", "Iran", "Mexico", "Russia"], "correctOption": 0}, {"question": "What transforms high level source code into assembly or machine code?", "category": "Computer Science", "difficulty": "easy", "points": 10.0, "options": ["abstracter", "decoder", "embedder", "compiler"], "correctOption": 3}, {"question": "What is the second largest state in the USA?", "category": "Geography", "difficulty": "medium", "points": 20.0, "options": ["Oregon", "Florida", "California", "Texas"], "correctOption": 3}, {"question": "Which album cover did Andy Warhol design for the Rolling Stones?", "category": "Music", "difficulty": "medium", "points": 20.0, "options": ["Beggars Banquet", "Sticky Fingers", "Let it Bleed", "Exile on Main St"], "correctOption": 1}, {"question": "Which of these countries border Russia?", "category": "Geography", "difficulty": "medium", "points": 20.0, "options": ["Kyrgyzstan", "Uzbekistan", "Tajikistan", "North Korea"], "correctOption": 3}, {"question": "A technique in the construction of large language models is RLHF, which stands for Reinforcement Learning from ... ?", "category": "Computer Science", "difficulty": "hard", "points": 30.0, "options": ["Human Feedback", "Hidden Frequencies", "Heuristic Factorials", "Hypergeometric Faces"], "correctOption": 0}, {"question": "Euler's number (e) is the base of ... ?", "category": "Mathematics", "difficulty": "easy", "points": 10.0, "options": ["Natural logarithms", "Rational logarithms", "Complex logarithms", "Imaginary logarithms"], "correctOption": 0}, {"question": "Which method can be used to predict the probability of one out of two possible outcomes, based on one or more variables?", "category": "Mathematics", "difficulty": "medium", "points": 20.0, "options": ["Chi-squared test", "Logistic regression", "Dynamic scaling", "Linear regression"], "correctOption": 1}, {"question": "The language 'Egyptian Arabic' belongs to which language family?", "category": "Linguistics", "difficulty": "medium", "points": 20.0, "options": ["Austronesian", "Afroasiatic", "Dravidian", "Uralic"], "correctOption": 1}, {"question": "Which city is the most populated in South Africa?", "category": "Geography", "difficulty": "medium", "points": 20.0, "options": ["Durban", "Pretoria", "Cape Town", "Johannesburg"], "correctOption": 3}, {"question": "Which film won the Academy Award for Best Picture in 2003?", "category": "Movies", "difficulty": "medium", "points": 20.0, "options": ["The Lord of the Rings: The Return of the King", "Lost in Translation", "Master and Commander: The Far Side of the World", "Mystic River"], "correctOption": 0}, {"question": "Which song was originally recorded by Joni Mitchell and was later covered by Crosby, Stills, Nash & Young?", "category": "Music", "difficulty": "medium", "points": 20.0, "options": ["Our House", "Carry On", "Always Cut My Hair", "Woodstock"], "correctOption": 3}, {"question": "Gaborone is the capital city of which country?", "category": "Geography", "difficulty": "medium", "points": 20.0, "options": ["Malawi", "Botswana", "Eswatini", "Lesotho"], "correctOption": 1}, {"question": "Which philosopher famously said 'It is wrong always, everywhere and for everyone, to believe anything upon insufficient evidence' ?", "category": "Philosophy", "difficulty": "medium", "points": 20.0, "options": ["Aristoteles", "Friedrich Nietzsche", "Ludwig Wittgenstein", "W. K. Clifford"], "correctOption": 3}, {"question": "Which film contains the character 'Inspector Jacques Clouseau' ?", "category": "Movies", "difficulty": "medium", "points": 20.0, "options": ["Fargo", "The Treasure of the Sierra Madre", "Apocalypse Now", "The Pink Panther"], "correctOption": 3}, {"question": "The language 'Hindi' belongs to which language family?", "category": "Linguistics", "difficulty": "easy", "points": 10.0, "options": ["Indo-European", "Uralic", "Dravidian", "Austronesian"], "correctOption": 0}, {"question": "'Finding Nemo' was released in which year?", "category": "Movies", "difficulty": "medium", "points": 20.0, "options": ["2000", "1997", "2006", "2003"], "correctOption": 3}, {"question": "Which author wrote 'Strange Case of Dr. Jekyll and Mr. Hyde' ?", "category": "Literature", "difficulty": "medium", "points": 20.0, "options": ["Joseph Conrad", "Robert Louis Stevenson", "Agatha Christie", "Oscar Wilde"], "correctOption": 1}, {"question": "Who wrote 'The Hitchhiker's Guide to the Galaxy' ?", "category": "Literature", "difficulty": "easy", "points": 10.0, "options": ["Stephen King", "Douglas Adams", "Terry Pratchett", "John Grisham"], "correctOption": 1}, {"question": "The language 'Hausa' belongs to which language family?", "category": "Linguistics", "difficulty": "medium", "points": 20.0, "options": ["Austronesian", "Afroasiatic", "Niger-Congo", "Dravidian"], "correctOption": 1}, {"question": "How are domestic canines more commonly known?", "category": "Biology", "difficulty": "easy", "points": 10.0, "options": ["Dogs", "Foxes", "Wolves", "Cows"], "correctOption": 0}, {"question": "Golden Earring had which hit single in 1973?", "category": "Music", "difficulty": "hard", "points": 30.0, "options": ["Radar Love", "No For An Answer", "Long Blond Animal", "Eight Miles High"], "correctOption": 0}, {"question": "In which year was the Beatles' \"Sgt. Pepper's Lonely Hearts Club Band\" released?", "category": "Music", "difficulty": "easy", "points": 10.0, "options": ["1967", "1968", "1966", "1965"], "correctOption": 0}, {"question": "What is phonetics concerned with?", "category": "Linguistics", "difficulty": "easy", "points": 10.0, "options": ["Grammar", "Writing", "Sounds", "Meaning"], "correctOption": 2}, {"question": "Who was considered the 'Father of Linguistics', a Swiss guy, who authored the seminal book entitled 'Course in General Linguistics' ?", "category": "Linguistics", "difficulty": "medium", "points": 20.0, "options": ["Leonard Bloomfield", "Noam Chomsky", "Ferdinand de Saussure", "William James"], "correctOption": 2}, {"question": "What animals can breathe \"with their cheeks\" ?", "category": "Biology", "difficulty": "easy", "points": 10.0, "options": ["Insects", "Birds", "Mammals", "Amphibians"], "correctOption": 3}, {"question": "Arabic belongs to the ...", "category": "Linguistics", "difficulty": "easy", "points": 10.0, "options": ["Semitic languages", "Berber languages", "Nubian languages", "Turkic languages"], "correctOption": 0}, {"question": "What is the derivative of f(x)=sin(x) ?", "category": "Mathematics", "difficulty": "easy", "points": 10.0, "options": ["-cos(x)", "tan(x)", "cot(x)", "cos(x)"], "correctOption": 3}, {"question": "Which is a synonym of 'penitent' ?", "category": "Linguistics", "difficulty": "hard", "points": 30.0, "options": ["contrite", "candent", "impolite", "diffident"], "correctOption": 0}, {"question": "What can be a possible cause for packet loss in the Internet ?", "category": "Computer Science", "difficulty": "hard", "points": 30.0, "options": ["Phishing attack", "Network congestion", "Receive window too large", "Checksum is in binary"], "correctOption": 1}, {"question": "What is the largest species of shark?", "category": "Biology", "difficulty": "medium", "points": 20.0, "options": ["Great White Shark", "Tiger Shark", "Hammerhead Shark", "Whale Shark"], "correctOption": 3}, {"question": "Which animal is known for its ability to change color to blend into its surroundings?", "category": "Biology", "difficulty": "easy", "points": 10.0, "options": ["Peacock", "Chameleon", "Octopus", "Flamingo"], "correctOption": 1}, {"question": "What is the primary defense mechanism of a skunk?", "category": "Biology", "difficulty": "easy", "points": 10.0, "options": ["Playing dead", "Camouflage", "Spraying a foul-smelling liquid", "Loud screeching"], "correctOption": 2}, {"question": "How many species of skunks are there?", "category": "Biology", "difficulty": "hard", "points": 30.0, "options": ["10", "12", "2", "4"], "correctOption": 1}, {"question": "What does \"CPU\" stand for in computer terminology?", "category": "Computer Science", "difficulty": "easy", "points": 10.0, "options": ["Control Program Utility", "Computer Personal Unit", "Central Processing Unit", "Central Power Unit"], "correctOption": 2}, {"question": "Which programming language is primarily used for web development on the client side?", "category": "Computer Science", "difficulty": "easy", "points": 10.0, "options": ["Java", "JavaScript", "Python", "C++"], "correctOption": 1}, {"question": "In computer networking, what does the term \"latency\" refer to?", "category": "Computer Science", "difficulty": "medium", "points": 20.0, "options": ["The amount of data transmitted over a network", "The number of devices connected to a network", "The time it takes for data to travel from the source to the destination", "The maximum bandwidth available in a network"], "correctOption": 2}, {"question": "Which significant historical event took place in Augsburg in 1555?", "category": "History", "difficulty": "medium", "points": 20.0, "options": [" The beginning of the Thirty Years' War", "The signing of the Treaty of Augsburg", "The Augsburg Peace of Religion", "The establishment of the Augsburg Confession"], "correctOption": 2}, {"question": "What is the value of the derivative of the function  \ud835\udc53 ( \ud835\udc65 ) = 3 \ud835\udc65 2 \u2212 5 \ud835\udc65 + 4 f(x)=3x  2  \u22125x+4 at the point  \ud835\udc65 = 2 x=2?", "category": "Mathematics", "difficulty": "medium", "points": 20.0, "options": ["7", "5", "10", "1"], "correctOption": 0}, {"question": "What is the fundamental theorem of algebra?", "category": "Mathematics", "difficulty": "hard", "points": 30.0, "options": ["Every polynomial can be factored into linear factors.", "The sum of the angles in a triangle is 180 degrees. ", "The product of the roots of a polynomial is equal to the constant term.", "Every polynomial equation of degree n has exactly n roots in the complex number system."], "correctOption": 3}, {"question": "What is the profession of the character Sean Maguire, played by Robin Williams, in Good Will Hunting?", "category": "Movies", "difficulty": "easy", "points": 10.0, "options": ["Psychologist", "Professor", "Mathematician", "Carpenter"], "correctOption": 0}, {"question": "What is the primary focus of the film My Own Private Idaho?", "category": "Movies", "difficulty": "medium", "points": 20.0, "options": ["A road trip across America for a music festival.", "The journey of two friends who are also hustlers.", "The life of a successful businessman.", "A family's struggle with mental illness."], "correctOption": 1}, {"question": "Which of the following films is directed by Alejandro Gonz\u00e1lez I\u00f1\u00e1rritu?", "category": "Movies", "difficulty": "medium", "points": 20.0, "options": ["Birdman", "The Revenant", "Babel", "All of the above"], "correctOption": 3}, {"question": "What major event took place in Algeria from 1954 to 1962?", "category": "History", "difficulty": "medium", "points": 20.0, "options": ["The Algerian Civil War", "The establishment of the Algerian Republic", "The Algerian War of Independenc", "The Battle of Algiers"], "correctOption": 2}, {"question": "What language family does Tigrinya belong to?", "category": "Linguistics", "difficulty": "medium", "points": 20.0, "options": ["Sino-Tibetan", "Indo-European", "Niger-Congo", "Afro-Asiatic"], "correctOption": 3}, {"question": "What was the significance of the Battle of Adwa in 1896 for Ethiopia?", "category": "History", "difficulty": "hard", "points": 30.0, "options": ["It secured Ethiopian sovereignty against Italian invasion.", " It led to the establishment of the Ethiopian Empire.", " It was the first time Ethiopia was colonized.", "It marked the end of the Ethiopian Civil War."], "correctOption": 0}, {"question": "What was the title of King Crimson's debut album released in 1969?", "category": "Music", "difficulty": "medium", "points": 20.0, "options": ["Larks' Tongues in Aspic", "In the Court of the Crimson King", "Discipline", "Red"], "correctOption": 1}, {"question": "Which of the following novels is considered David Foster Wallace's magnum opus?", "category": "Literature", "difficulty": "medium", "points": 20.0, "options": ["Infinite Jest", "Brief Interviews with Hideous Men", "The Broom of the System", "Girl with Curious Hair"], "correctOption": 0}, {"question": "Which prestigious award did Elfriede Jelinek receive in 2004?", "category": "Literature", "difficulty": "medium", "points": 20.0, "options": ["Pulitzer Prize", "Nobel Prize in Literature", "Goethe Prize", "Booker Prize"], "correctOption": 1}, {"question": "What was the significance of Ravenna during the Roman Empire?", "category": "History", "difficulty": "easy", "points": 10.0, "options": ["It was the location of the Colosseum.", "It was the capital of the Western Roman Empire.", "It served as the main naval base of the Roman fleet.", "It was the birthplace of Julius Caesar. "], "correctOption": 1}, {"question": "Which of the following philosophers is most commonly associated with existentialism?", "category": "Philosophy", "difficulty": "easy", "points": 10.0, "options": ["Jean-Paul Sartre", "Immanuel Kant", "Karl Marx", "Friedrich Nietzsche"], "correctOption": 0}, {"question": "What is Gottlob Frege primarily known for in the field of philosophy?", "category": "Philosophy", "difficulty": "medium", "points": 20.0, "options": ["Establishing the concept of the unconscious", "Introducing existentialism", "Developing the theory of relativity", "Founding modern logic and philosophy of language"], "correctOption": 3}, {"question": "Which concept is most closely associated with Horkheimer and Adorno in their critique of culture and society?", "category": "Philosophy", "difficulty": "medium", "points": 20.0, "options": ["Crisis of Meaning", "Pragmatism", "The \"Social Contract\"", "The \"Culture Industry\""], "correctOption": 3}, {"question": "What is the main theme of Rousseau's work The Social Contract?", "category": "Philosophy", "difficulty": "medium", "points": 20.0, "options": ["The importance of individual freedom and the general will", "The inevitability of social inequality", "The necessity of absolute monarchy", "The rejection of private property"], "correctOption": 0}, {"question": "What is the primary diet of raccoons (Procyon lotor)?", "category": "Biology", "difficulty": "medium", "points": 20.0, "options": ["Omnivorous, eating both plant and animal matter", "Herbivorous, primarily feeding on plants", "Carnivorous, primarily feeding on other animals", "Insectivorous, primarily feeding on insects"], "correctOption": 0}, {"question": "What is a unique reproductive feature of seahorses (Hippocampus)?", "category": "Biology", "difficulty": "hard", "points": 30.0, "options": ["They have a symbiotic relationship with other fish for reproduction.", "They lay eggs in a nest.", "They reproduce asexually. ", "The males carry and incubate the eggs in a pouch."], "correctOption": 3}, {"question": "What is one of the most distinctive social behaviors of bonobos (Pan paniscus)?", "category": "Biology", "difficulty": "easy", "points": 10.0, "options": ["They exhibit strong male dominance hierarchies.", "They primarily use tools for foraging. ", "They use sexual behavior to resolve conflicts and strengthen social bonds.", "They are strictly solitary animals."], "correctOption": 2}, {"question": "What major event occurred in the Democratic Republic of the Congo in 1960?", "category": "History", "difficulty": "easy", "points": 10.0, "options": ["The Congo Crisis and the declaration of independence from Belgium", "The rise of Mobutu Sese Seko to power", "The first democratic elections", "The establishment of Belgian colonial rule"], "correctOption": 0}, {"question": "Which of the following works is written by Dimitri Verhulst?", "category": "Literature", "difficulty": "hard", "points": 30.0, "options": ["The Book of Chameleons", "The Sorrow of Belgium", "The Discovery of Heaven", "The Misfortunates"], "correctOption": 3}, {"question": "What is the primary reason for the hibernation of dormice (Gliridae), commonly known as \"Siebenschl\u00e4fer\"?", "category": "Biology", "difficulty": "medium", "points": 20.0, "options": ["To avoid predators", "To survive food scarcity during winter", "To migrate to warmer climates", "To enter a mating period"], "correctOption": 1}, {"question": "Which of the following mechanisms do Venus flytraps (Dionaea muscipula) use to capture their prey?", "category": "Biology", "difficulty": "medium", "points": 20.0, "options": ["Snap trapping", "Adhesive trapping", "Passive trapping", "Pitfall trapping"], "correctOption": 0}, {"question": "Which novel is J.D. Salinger best known for, featuring the character Holden Caulfield?", "category": "Literature", "difficulty": "easy", "points": 10.0, "options": ["Nine Stories", "The Catcher in the Rye", "Raise High the Roof Beam, Carpenter", "Franny and Zooey"], "correctOption": 1}, {"question": "What is the scientific name for the giant sequoia, commonly known as the mammoth tree?", "category": "Biology", "difficulty": "easy", "points": 10.0, "options": ["Sequoia sempervirens", "Metasequoia glyptostroboides", "Sequoiadendron giganteum", "Taxodium distichum"], "correctOption": 2}, {"question": "Which of the following novels was written by Clemens J. Setz?", "category": "Literature", "difficulty": "hard", "points": 30.0, "options": ["The Hour of the Star", "The Floating Theatre", "The Invention of Morel", "Indigo"], "correctOption": 3}, {"question": "What is the primary purpose of eigenvalues and eigenvectors in linear algebra?", "category": "Mathematics", "difficulty": "hard", "points": 30.0, "options": ["To calculate the determinant of a matrix", "To solve systems of equations", "To analyze linear transformations and their effects on vector spaces", "To determine the rank of a matrix"], "correctOption": 2}, {"question": "Which of the following distributions is characterized by its bell-shaped curve and is commonly used in statistics?", "category": "Mathematics", "difficulty": "easy", "points": 10.0, "options": ["Binomial distribution", "Poisson distribution", "Exponential distribution", "Normal distribution"], "correctOption": 3}, {"question": "Which of the following novels is written by Tahar Ben Jelloun?", "category": "Literature", "difficulty": "hard", "points": 30.0, "options": ["The Name of the Rose", "This Blinding Absence of Light", "The Invisible Man", "The Sand Child"], "correctOption": 1}, {"question": "Which of the following authors is known for their significant contributions to Maghrebian literature?", "category": "Literature", "difficulty": "easy", "points": 10.0, "options": ["Naguib Mahfouz", "Mario Vargas Llosa", "Gabriel Garc\u00eda M\u00e1rquez", "Assia Djebar"], "correctOption": 3}, {"question": "When was Heidelberg University founded?", "category": "History", "difficulty": "medium", "points": 20.0, "options": ["1453", "1386", "1600", "1750"], "correctOption": 1}, {"question": "Who wrote the famous poem \"Heidelberg\" and visited the city several times in the 19th century?", "category": "Literature", "difficulty": "medium", "points": 20.0, "options": ["Mark Twain", "Johann Wolfgang von Goethe", "Friedrich Schiller", "Heinrich Heine"], "correctOption": 0}, {"question": "In which movie did Matt Damon portray an astronaut stranded on Mars?", "category": "Movies", "difficulty": "easy", "points": 10.0, "options": ["Interstellar", "Elysium", "Gravity", "The Martian"], "correctOption": 3}, {"question": "What is the name of the famous street depicted in Fellini's La Dolce Vita?", "category": "Movies", "difficulty": "medium", "points": 20.0, "options": ["Via Appia", "Via del Corso", "Via Condotti", "Via Veneto"], "correctOption": 3}, {"question": "Which of the following films is a political satire directed by Nanni Moretti?", "category": "Movies", "difficulty": "medium", "points": 20.0, "options": ["Il Caimano", "Caro Diario", "La Messa \u00e8 Finita", "Mia Madre"], "correctOption": 0}, {"question": "Zabriskie Point is famous for its final sequence. What happens during this scene?", "category": "Movies", "difficulty": "medium", "points": 20.0, "options": ["A car chase through the desert", "A protest turns violent", "A house explodes in slow motion", "The protagonists escape to Mexico"], "correctOption": 2}, {"question": "What is the main theme of Ken Park?", "category": "Movies", "difficulty": "medium", "points": 20.0, "options": ["Teenage alienation and dysfunctional families", "Political activism and rebellion", "Drug addiction and recovery", "Urban crime and corruption"], "correctOption": 0}, {"question": "Which character is an undercover cop infiltrating the Irish mob in The Departed?", "category": "Movies", "difficulty": "hard", "points": 30.0, "options": ["Sean Dignam", "Billy Costigan", "Frank Costello", "Colin Sullivan"], "correctOption": 1}, {"question": "What is the meaning of the standard deviation in a dataset?", "category": "Mathematics", "difficulty": "medium", "points": 20.0, "options": ["The measure of the spread or dispersion of the data", "The range of the dataset", "The average of the data points", "The square of the mean"], "correctOption": 0}, {"question": "What is the determinant of a square matrix used to determine?", "category": "Mathematics", "difficulty": "medium", "points": 20.0, "options": ["The trace of the matrix", "The eigenvalues of the matrix", "Whether the matrix is invertible", "The rank of the matrix"], "correctOption": 2}, {"question": "What is the main focus of Wittgenstein's early work, Tractatus Logico-Philosophicus?", "category": "Philosophy", "difficulty": "medium", "points": 20.0, "options": ["Ethics and morality", "The nature of time", "The existence of God", "Language and its relation to reality"], "correctOption": 3}, {"question": "What is the primary concern of linguistic philosophy?", "category": "Philosophy", "difficulty": "medium", "points": 20.0, "options": ["The history of language development", "The study of phonetics and grammar", "The classification of languages", "The relationship between language, thought, and reality"], "correctOption": 3}, {"question": "What is Giambattista Vico's view on the nature of human history?", "category": "Philosophy", "difficulty": "hard", "points": 30.0, "options": ["History is linear and progresses towards a specific goal", "History is solely determined by economic factors", "History is completely random and lacks any discernible order", "History is cyclical and characterized by recurring themes and patterns"], "correctOption": 3}, {"question": "Which philosopher proposed the idea that history is a struggle between the ruling class and the oppressed class?", "category": "Philosophy", "difficulty": "easy", "points": 10.0, "options": ["Karl Marx", "Alexis de Tocqueville", "Max Weber", "Michel Foucault"], "correctOption": 0}, {"question": "What significant event occurred in 711 AD that impacted the history of Andalusia?", "category": "History", "difficulty": "easy", "points": 10.0, "options": ["The arrival of the Moors and the beginning of Muslim rule", "The Reconquista", "The establishment of the Spanish Inquisition", "The discovery of America"], "correctOption": 0}, {"question": "Which event in 1979 dramatically changed the political landscape of Iran?", "category": "History", "difficulty": "easy", "points": 10.0, "options": ["The Constitutional Revolution", "The Iran-Iraq War", "The Anglo-Persian War", "The Islamic Revolution"], "correctOption": 3}, {"question": "What was the Aksum Empire primarily known for?", "category": "History", "difficulty": "hard", "points": 30.0, "options": ["Its advanced agricultural techniques and trade networks", "Its vast collection of written literature", "Its conquests of neighboring territories", "Its naval power and exploration"], "correctOption": 0}, {"question": "Which of the following empires is associated with the rise of Timbuktu as a prominent city?", "category": "History", "difficulty": "easy", "points": 10.0, "options": ["The Ottoman Empire", "The Byzantine Empire", "The Roman Empire", "The Mali Empire"], "correctOption": 3}, {"question": "Timbuktu is located in which present-day country?", "category": "Geography", "difficulty": "medium", "points": 20.0, "options": ["Senegal", "Mali", "Nigeria", "Burkina Faso"], "correctOption": 1}, {"question": "What was the capital of the Byzantine Empire?", "category": "History", "difficulty": "easy", "points": 10.0, "options": ["Athens", "Alexandria", "Rome", "Constantinople"], "correctOption": 3}, {"question": "What is a neural network?", "category": "Computer Science", "difficulty": "medium", "points": 20.0, "options": ["A computational model inspired by the way biological neural networks in the human brain process information", "A hardware component of a computer", "A type of computer virus", "A network of interconnected computers"], "correctOption": 0}, {"question": "Which novel is based on Thomas Mann's own family background and examines the decline of a wealthy merchant family?", "category": "Literature", "difficulty": "easy", "points": 10.0, "options": ["The Magic Mountain", "Buddenbrooks", "Confessions of Felix Krull", "The Holy Sinner"], "correctOption": 1}, {"question": "In which city was Goethe born?", "category": "Literature", "difficulty": "medium", "points": 20.0, "options": ["Stuttgart", "Frankfurt am Main", "Weimar", "Berlin"], "correctOption": 1}, {"question": "Sloths are known for their slow metabolism. Approximately how long can it take for a sloth to digest food?", "category": "Biology", "difficulty": "medium", "points": 20.0, "options": ["1-2 weeks", "30-40 hours", "2-3 hours", "12-24 hours"], "correctOption": 1}, {"question": "What family do dogs, wolves, and foxes belong to?", "category": "Biology", "difficulty": "easy", "points": 10.0, "options": ["Canidae", "Ursidae", "Mustelidae", "Felidae"], "correctOption": 0}, {"question": "Domestic pigs are known for their intelligence. Which of the following animals are they often compared to in terms of cognitive abilities?", "category": "Biology", "difficulty": "medium", "points": 20.0, "options": ["Horses", "Dogs", "Cows", "Cats"], "correctOption": 1}, {"question": "What does \"open\" software mean?", "category": "Computer Science", "difficulty": "medium", "points": 20.0, "options": ["Software that is free of charge", "Software whose source code is available for modification and distribution", "Software that is only available online", "Software that requires a license"], "correctOption": 1}, {"question": "Which sorting algorithm is known for its efficiency in large datasets and is commonly implemented in many programming languages?", "category": "Computer Science", "difficulty": "medium", "points": 20.0, "options": ["Bubble Sort", "Insertion Sort", "Quick Sort", "Selection Sort"], "correctOption": 2}, {"question": "Which of the following is a fundamental data structure in computer science used to store a collection of items?", "category": "Computer Science", "difficulty": "easy", "points": 10.0, "options": ["Array", "All of the above", "Tree", "Graph"], "correctOption": 1}, {"question": "Which philosophical tradition is Hegel associated with?", "category": "Philosophy", "difficulty": "medium", "points": 20.0, "options": ["Existentialism", "Rationalism", "Empiricism", "Idealism"], "correctOption": 3}, {"question": "What is the title of Spinoza's most significant work, where he presents his philosophical ideas on God, nature, and ethics?", "category": "Philosophy", "difficulty": "medium", "points": 20.0, "options": ["Axioms of Religion", "Tractatus Politicus", "Theological-Political Treatise", "Ethics"], "correctOption": 3}, {"question": "Meister Eckhart was a prominent figure in which philosophical and theological tradition?", "category": "Philosophy", "difficulty": "medium", "points": 20.0, "options": ["Christian Mysticism", "Rationalism", "Scholasticism", "Sufism"], "correctOption": 0}, {"question": "What is the definition of a limit in the context of calculus?", "category": "Mathematics", "difficulty": "medium", "points": 20.0, "options": ["The value that a function approaches as the input approaches a certain point.", "The area under a curve.", "The highest value of a function.", "The rate of change of a function. "], "correctOption": 0}, {"question": "Which of the following is a characteristic of a normal distribution?", "category": "Mathematics", "difficulty": "medium", "points": 20.0, "options": ["It has two peaks.", "It is skewed to the right.", "It has a mean, median, and mode that are all equal.", "It is uniform."], "correctOption": 2}, {"question": "In calculus, what does the derivative of a function represent?", "category": "Mathematics", "difficulty": "medium", "points": 20.0, "options": ["The instantaneous rate of change of the function.", "The area under the curve of the function.", "The maximum value of the function.", "The average rate of change of the function."], "correctOption": 0}, {"question": "Which of the following is one of Camille Saint-Sa\u00ebns's most famous works?", "category": "Music", "difficulty": "medium", "points": 20.0, "options": ["The Rite of Spring", "Carnival of the Animals", "The Nutcracker Suite", "The Four Seasons"], "correctOption": 1}, {"question": "Which instrument did John Coltrane play?", "category": "Music", "difficulty": "easy", "points": 10.0, "options": ["Trombone", "Saxophone", "Piano", "Trumpet"], "correctOption": 1}, {"question": "Holst composed \"The Planets\" between 1914 and 1917. How many movements are in this suite?", "category": "Music", "difficulty": "hard", "points": 30.0, "options": ["9", "7", "8", "5"], "correctOption": 1}, {"question": "In which film did Woody Allen win an Academy Award for Best Original Screenplay?", "category": "Movies", "difficulty": "medium", "points": 20.0, "options": ["Hannah and Her Sisters", "Match Point", "Annie Hall", "Crimes and Misdemeanors"], "correctOption": 2}, {"question": "Which of the following films is directed by Pedro Almod\u00f3var?", "category": "Movies", "difficulty": "medium", "points": 20.0, "options": ["Pan's Labyrinth", "The Sea Inside", "Talk to Her", "Am\u00e9lie"], "correctOption": 2}, {"question": "Which of the following films directed by Herzog features a narrative about the construction of an opera house in the Amazon rainforest?", "category": "Movies", "difficulty": "medium", "points": 20.0, "options": ["Nosferatu", "My Best Fiend", "Stroszek", "Fitzcarraldo"], "correctOption": 3}, {"question": "Thomas Bernhard often criticized which aspect of Austrian culture in his writings?", "category": "Literature", "difficulty": "medium", "points": 20.0, "options": ["Nationalism and conformity", "Environmental issues", "The education system", "The arts"], "correctOption": 0}, {"question": "What is the title of Hemingway's novella that tells the story of an old fisherman and his struggle with a giant marlin?", "category": "Literature", "difficulty": "easy", "points": 10.0, "options": ["The Snows of Kilimanjaro", "A Moveable Feast", "Islands in the Stream", "The Old Man and the Sea"], "correctOption": 3}, {"question": "What is the study of the rules governing the structure of sentences in a language called?", "category": "Linguistics", "difficulty": "medium", "points": 20.0, "options": ["Pragmatics", "Semantics", "Syntax", "Morphology"], "correctOption": 2}, {"question": "In phonetics, what is the term for the smallest unit of sound that can distinguish meaning in a language?", "category": "Linguistics", "difficulty": "easy", "points": 10.0, "options": ["Phoneme", "Morpheme", "Allophone", "Grapheme"], "correctOption": 0}, {"question": "Which theory posits that the structure of a language influences its speakers' worldview or cognition?", "category": "Linguistics", "difficulty": "hard", "points": 30.0, "options": ["Relativity Hypothesis (Sapir-Whorf Hypothesis)", "Generative Grammar", "Universal Grammar", "Structuralism"], "correctOption": 0}, {"question": "What is the approximate length of the Niger River, making it one of the longest rivers in Africa?", "category": "Geography", "difficulty": "medium", "points": 20.0, "options": ["1600 kilometers", "4200 kilometers", "5800 kilometers", "2600 kilometers"], "correctOption": 1}, {"question": "The Danube Delta, a UNESCO World Heritage site, is located in which country?", "category": "Geography", "difficulty": "medium", "points": 20.0, "options": ["Bulgaria", "Romania", "Serbia", "Hungary"], "correctOption": 1}, {"question": "Which of the following countries shares a border with Niger?", "category": "Geography", "difficulty": "medium", "points": 20.0, "options": ["Nigeria", "All of the above", "Algeria", "Mali"], "correctOption": 1}, {"question": "Which city, known as a center of learning and trade, was part of the Mali Empire?", "category": "History", "difficulty": "easy", "points": 10.0, "options": ["Timbuktu", "Cairo", "Marrakech", "Lagos"], "correctOption": 0}, {"question": "What was the primary military tactic used by the Mongol armies that contributed to their success?", "category": "History", "difficulty": "easy", "points": 10.0, "options": ["Fast cavalry and mobility", "Siege warfare", "Naval warfare", "Guerrilla warfare"], "correctOption": 0}, {"question": "Which of the following cat breeds is known for being hairless?", "category": "Biology", "difficulty": "easy", "points": 10.0, "options": ["Sphynx", "Maine Coon", "Persian", "Siamese"], "correctOption": 0}, {"question": "Which of these North American animals is known for its role in shaping river ecosystems by building dams?", "category": "Biology", "difficulty": "easy", "points": 10.0, "options": ["Grizzly Bear", "Gray Wolf", "American Bison", "North American Beaver"], "correctOption": 3}, {"question": "In the context of database management, what does the acronym ACID stand for?", "category": "Computer Science", "difficulty": "hard", "points": 30.0, "options": ["Availability, Concurrency, Integrity, Deletion", "Authorization, Compression, Inference, Distribution", "Asynchronous, Centralized, Inverse, Denormalized", "Atomicity, Consistency, Isolation, Durability"], "correctOption": 3}, {"question": "Which algorithmic paradigm does the Dijkstra's algorithm for shortest paths primarily rely on?", "category": "Computer Science", "difficulty": "hard", "points": 30.0, "options": ["Backtracking", "Greedy Algorithm", "Divide and Conquer", "Dynamic Programming"], "correctOption": 1}, {"question": "Which is the longest mountain range in Africa?", "category": "Geography", "difficulty": "medium", "points": 20.0, "options": ["Atlas Mountains", "Drakensberg Mountains", "Rwenzori Mountains", "Simien Mountains"], "correctOption": 0}, {"question": "What is the world highest mountain?", "category": "Geography", "difficulty": "easy", "points": 10.0, "options": ["Mount Everest", "K2", "Denali", "Kilimanjaro"], "correctOption": 0}, {"question": "Which empire was known for its extensive trade networks and cultural exchanges during the early modern period in India?", "category": "History", "difficulty": "medium", "points": 20.0, "options": ["Gupta Empire", "Mughal Empire", "Chola Dynasty", "Maurya Empire"], "correctOption": 1}, {"question": "Which civilization is known for its advanced architectural achievements and the creation of the calendar, and was prominent in Mexico before the Spanish conquest?", "category": "History", "difficulty": "easy", "points": 10.0, "options": ["Inca", "Aztec", "Olmec", "Maya"], "correctOption": 3}, {"question": "Which of the following language families includes languages such as Russian, Polish, and Czech?", "category": "Linguistics", "difficulty": "easy", "points": 10.0, "options": ["Slavic", "Germanic", "Romance", "Semitic"], "correctOption": 0}, {"question": "What is the primary characteristic that defines a language as belonging to the Sino-Tibetan language family?", "category": "Linguistics", "difficulty": "medium", "points": 20.0, "options": ["It is tonal and primarily spoken in East Asia.", "It has no grammatical structure.", " It includes only languages spoken in China.", "It uses an alphabetic writing system."], "correctOption": 0}, {"question": "Which theorem states that every continuous function on a closed interval attains its maximum and minimum values?", "category": "Mathematics", "difficulty": "hard", "points": 30.0, "options": ["Intermediate Value Theorem", "Bolzano-Weierstrass Theorem", "Extreme Value Theorem", "Mean Value Theorem"], "correctOption": 2}, {"question": "Which theorem provides a method for approximating the value of a function using its derivatives at a single point?", "category": "Mathematics", "difficulty": "medium", "points": 20.0, "options": ["Fundamental Theorem of Calculus", "Taylor's Theorem", "L'H\u00f4pital's Rule", "Pythagorean Theorem"], "correctOption": 1}, {"question": "What is the central theme of Pedro Almod\u00f3var's film \"Todo sobre mi madre\" (All About My Mother)?", "category": "Movies", "difficulty": "medium", "points": 20.0, "options": ["The challenges of aging", "The impact of war on families", "The search of a lost child", "The complexities of motherhood and identity"], "correctOption": 3}, {"question": "Which Alfred Hitchcock film features a character named Marion Crane, who becomes the victim of a notorious shower scene?", "category": "Movies", "difficulty": "easy", "points": 10.0, "options": ["Vertigo", "Rear Window", "North By Northwest", "Psycho"], "correctOption": 3}, {"question": "What is a primary characteristic that distinguishes heavy metal music from hard rock?", "category": "Music", "difficulty": "easy", "points": 10.0, "options": ["Use of clean vocals", "Inclusion of acoustic instruments", "Emphasis on melodic hooks", "Heavier guitar riffs and darker themes"], "correctOption": 3}, {"question": "Which Focus album, released in 1971, features the hit single \"Hocus Pocus\"?", "category": "Music", "difficulty": "hard", "points": 30.0, "options": ["Focus III", "Moving Waves", "Hamburger Concerto", "Live at the Rainbow"], "correctOption": 1}, {"question": "Which philosopher is known for the statement \"I think, therefore I am\"?", "category": "Philosophy", "difficulty": "easy", "points": 10.0, "options": ["John Locke", "Ren\u00e9 Descartes", "Friedrich Nietzsche", "Immanuel Kant"], "correctOption": 1}, {"question": "Schelling primarily associated with, emphasizing the idea of nature as a dynamic and self-revealing process?", "category": "Philosophy", "difficulty": "medium", "points": 20.0, "options": ["Dialectical Materialism", "Philosophy of Nature", "Transcendental Idealism", "Absolute Idealism"], "correctOption": 1}, {"question": "What scientific suborder does the family Hyaenidae belong to ?", "category": "Biology", "difficulty": "medium", "points": 20.0, "options": ["Ciconiiformes", "Caniformia", "Haplorhini", "Feliformia"], "correctOption": 3}, {"question": "What is the scientific name of the cheetah?", "category": "Biology", "difficulty": "hard", "points": 30.0, "options": ["Acinonyx jubatus", "Panthera onca", "Felis catus", "Lynx rufus"], "correctOption": 0}, {"question": "What bird is born with claws on its wing digits?", "category": "Biology", "difficulty": "hard", "points": 30.0, "options": ["Cormorant", "Cassowary", "Secretary bird", "Hoatzin"], "correctOption": 3}, {"question": "Which of these is not a layer in the OSI model for data communications?", "category": "Computer Science", "difficulty": "hard", "points": 30.0, "options": ["Connection Layer", "Application Layer", "Transport Layer", "Physical Layer"], "correctOption": 0}, {"question": "What port does HTTP run on?", "category": "Computer Science", "difficulty": "hard", "points": 30.0, "options": ["443", "80", "23", "53"], "correctOption": 1}, {"question": "What does the International System of Quantities refer 1024 bytes as?", "category": "Computer Science", "difficulty": "hard", "points": 30.0, "options": ["Kylobyte", "Kilobyte", "Kibibyte", "Kelobyte"], "correctOption": 2}, {"question": "Which of these is NOT a real tectonic plate?", "category": "Geography", "difficulty": "hard", "points": 30.0, "options": ["Nazca Plate", "Eurasian Plate", "Atlantic Plate", "North American Plate"], "correctOption": 2}, {"question": "What is the most populous Muslim-majority nation in 2010?", "category": "Geography", "difficulty": "hard", "points": 30.0, "options": ["Sudan", "Iran", "Saudi Arabia", "Indonesia"], "correctOption": 3}, {"question": "How many countries border Kyrgyzstan?", "category": "Geography", "difficulty": "hard", "points": 30.0, "options": ["1", "3", "6", "4"], "correctOption": 3}, {"question": "The Second Boer War in 1899 was fought where?", "category": "History", "difficulty": "medium", "points": 20.0, "options": ["South Africa", "Argentina", "Nepal", "Bulgaria"], "correctOption": 0}, {"question": "Which day did World War I begin?", "category": "History", "difficulty": "hard", "points": 30.0, "options": ["June 28", "January 28", "July 28", "April 28"], "correctOption": 2}, {"question": "How many women joined the United States Armed Services during World War II?", "category": "History", "difficulty": "hard", "points": 30.0, "options": ["500000", "100000", "350000", "250000"], "correctOption": 2}, {"question": "What is the approximate value of mathematical constant e?", "category": "Mathematics", "difficulty": "medium", "points": 20.0, "options": ["3.14", "2.72", "1.62", "1.41"], "correctOption": 1}, {"question": "What is the smallest number that can be expressed as the sum of two positive cubes in two different ways?", "category": "Mathematics", "difficulty": "hard", "points": 30.0, "options": ["91", "1729", "4104", "561"], "correctOption": 1}, {"question": "The decimal number 31 in hexadecimal would be what?", "category": "Mathematics", "difficulty": "medium", "points": 20.0, "options": ["1F", "3D", "2E", "1B"], "correctOption": 0}, {"question": "In which African country was the 2006 film 'Blood Diamond' mostly set in?", "category": "Movies", "difficulty": "medium", "points": 20.0, "options": ["Sierra Leone", "Burkina Faso", "Central African Republic", "Liberia"], "correctOption": 0}, {"question": "What was the first feature-length computer-animated movie?", "category": "Movies", "difficulty": "easy", "points": 10.0, "options": ["Lion king", "Toy Story", "Tron", "101 Dalmatians"], "correctOption": 1}, {"question": "Who directed \"E.T. the Extra-Terrestrial\" (1982)?", "category": "Movies", "difficulty": "easy", "points": 10.0, "options": ["Tim Burton", "Steven Spielberg", "James Cameron", "Stanley Kubrick"], "correctOption": 1}, {"question": "Who was the guitarist in the band \"The Doors\"?", "category": "Music", "difficulty": "medium", "points": 20.0, "options": ["John Densmore", "Jim Morrison", "Ray Manzarek", "Robby Krieger"], "correctOption": 3}, {"question": "What was the name of Pink Floyd's first studio album?", "category": "Music", "difficulty": "medium", "points": 20.0, "options": ["The Piper at the Gates of Dawn", "More", "Atom Heart Mother", "Ummagumma"], "correctOption": 0}, {"question": "What was The Velvet Underground's first album called?", "category": "Music", "difficulty": "medium", "points": 20.0, "options": ["Loaded", "White Light-White Heat", "The Velvet Underground & Nico", "The Velvet Underground"], "correctOption": 2}, {"question": "Which author co-wrote \"The Communist Manifesto\" alongside Karl Marx?", "category": "Philosophy", "difficulty": "easy", "points": 10.0, "options": ["Ludwig Wittgenstein", "Arthur Schopenhauer", "Friedrich Engels", "Gottlob Frege"], "correctOption": 2}, {"question": "The novel \"Of Mice And Men\" was written by what author?", "category": "Literature", "difficulty": "easy", "points": 10.0, "options": ["George Orwell", "John Steinbeck", "Harper Lee", "Mark Twain"], "correctOption": 1}, {"question": "In the year 1818, novelist Mary Shelly is credited with writing a fiction novel and creating this infamous character.", "category": "Literature", "difficulty": "easy", "points": 10.0, "options": ["The Thing", "Dracula", "The Invisible Man", "Frankenstein's monster"], "correctOption": 3}, {"question": "Who wrote the novel \"Moby Dick\"?", "category": "Literature", "difficulty": "easy", "points": 10.0, "options": ["William Shakespeare", "Herman Melville", "William Golding", "J. R. R. Tolkien"], "correctOption": 1}, {"question": "Which concept is central to Schopenhauer's philosophy and is described as the driving force behind all life and phenomena?", "category": "Philosophy", "difficulty": "medium", "points": 20.0, "options": ["Reason", "Knowledge", "Will", "Being"], "correctOption": 2}, {"question": "In Thus Spoke Zarathustra, what concept does Nietzsche introduce as a model for personal growth, symbolizing an ideal of strength, creativity, and self-overcoming?", "category": "Philosophy", "difficulty": "medium", "points": 20.0, "options": ["Apollonian and Dionysian", "\u00dcbermensch (Overman)", "Slave Morality", "Eternal Recurrence"], "correctOption": 1}, {"question": "Which of these languages does not use articles?", "category": "Linguistics", "difficulty": "medium", "points": 20.0, "options": ["Swahili", "Arabic", "Italian", "Turkish"], "correctOption": 3}, {"question": "What is the term for a speech sound produced without any significant constriction of the airflow in the vocal tract?", "category": "Linguistics", "difficulty": "medium", "points": 20.0, "options": ["Plosive", "Vowel", "Affricate", "Fricative"], "correctOption": 1}, {"question": "In phonetics, which of the following describes a sound made by fully stopping the airflow and then releasing it, as in the sounds /p/ or /t/?", "category": "Linguistics", "difficulty": "hard", "points": 30.0, "options": ["Lateral", "Nasal", "Approximant", "Plosive"], "correctOption": 3}, {"question": "What is the average age at which women enter menopause?", "category": "Biology", "difficulty": "medium", "points": 20.0, "options": ["~51 years", "~46 years", "~39 years", "~64 years"], "correctOption": 0}, {"question": "\"hitherto\" means ... ?", "category": "Linguistics", "difficulty": "hard", "points": 30.0, "options": ["up until now", "before long", "in due course", "thereupon"], "correctOption": 0}, {"question": "Which word contains a velar consonant?", "category": "Linguistics", "difficulty": "hard", "points": 30.0, "options": ["they", "bee", "lie", "gay"], "correctOption": 3}, {"question": "How many bones does a white shark have in its body?", "category": "Biology", "difficulty": "hard", "points": 30.0, "options": ["216", "0", "56", "333"], "correctOption": 1}, {"question": "What philosopher wrote \"Leviathan\" ?", "category": "Philosophy", "difficulty": "medium", "points": 20.0, "options": ["Thomas Hobbes", "Karl Popper", "John Stuart Mill", "Bertrand Russell"], "correctOption": 0}, {"question": "Deep neural networks are so called, because they have multiple ... ?", "category": "Computer Science", "difficulty": "hard", "points": 30.0, "options": ["Clustered indices", "Hidden layers", "Markov chains", "Decision trees"], "correctOption": 1}, {"question": "Which fish spawns in freshwater, but spends its adult life at sea?", "category": "Biology", "difficulty": "hard", "points": 30.0, "options": ["Tuna", "Swordfish", "Salmon", "American eel"], "correctOption": 2}, {"question": "Which country occupied Albania from 1939 to 1943?", "category": "History", "difficulty": "medium", "points": 20.0, "options": ["Spain", "Yugoslavia", "Italy", "Romania"], "correctOption": 2}, {"question": "Which of these pairs of words are antonyms?", "category": "Linguistics", "difficulty": "hard", "points": 30.0, "options": ["destitute-bankrupt", "belligerent-pugnacious", "antiquated-archaic", "congenial-vitrolic"], "correctOption": 3}, {"question": "Which is an alternative to gradient descent when constructing artificial neural networks?", "category": "Computer Science", "difficulty": "hard", "points": 30.0, "options": ["Neuroevolution", "Exponential backoff", "Marzullo synchronisation", "Huffman coding"], "correctOption": 0}, {"question": "Which network encrypts and passes on data through random relays to ensure Internet anonymity?", "category": "Computer Science", "difficulty": "medium", "points": 20.0, "options": ["Tor", "Fub", "Jag", "Mig"], "correctOption": 0}, {"question": "Which of these philosophers lived in the 20th century?", "category": "Philosophy", "difficulty": "easy", "points": 10.0, "options": ["Arthur Schopenhauer", "Gottfried Leibniz", "René Descartes", "Karl Popper"], "correctOption": 3}, {"question": "Which of the following characteristics is unique to the traditional playing style of the Appalachian dulcimer compared to other stringed instruments?", "category": "Music", "difficulty": "medium", "points": 20.0, "options": ["It uses double-course strings exclusively", "It has frets that allow microtonal tuning.", "It is typically held and played flat on the lap.", "It is played with a bow rather than plucked."], "correctOption": 2}, {"question": "Which of the following bands was a key figure in the \"British Invasion,\" bringing British rock and pop music to the United States in the 1960s?", "category": "Music", "difficulty": "easy", "points": 10.0, "options": ["The Byrds", "The Rolling Stones", "The Beach Boys", "Creedence Clearwater Revival"], "correctOption": 1}, {"question": "Which music genre is Creedence Clearwater Revival most commonly associated with, blending rock and roll with Southern, blues, and country influences?", "category": "Music", "difficulty": "medium", "points": 20.0, "options": ["Folk Rock", "Southern Rock", "Psychedelic Rock", "Swamp Rock"], "correctOption": 3}, {"question": "Which of the following novels by John Irving tells the story of a writer reflecting on his life, love, and the influence of wrestling?", "category": "Literature", "difficulty": "medium", "points": 20.0, "options": ["The Cider House Rules", "A Prayer for Owen Meany", "Last Night in Twisted River", "The World According to Garp"], "correctOption": 3}, {"question": "In which film series did Tobey Maguire gain widespread fame for portraying a character with superhuman abilities and a strong sense of responsibility?", "category": "Movies", "difficulty": "medium", "points": 20.0, "options": ["The Matrix", "X-Men", "The Lord of the Rings", "Spider-Man"], "correctOption": 3}, {"question": "In which critically acclaimed film did River Phoenix portray a group of boys who go on a journey to find their missing friend, ultimately confronting issues of friendship and loss?", "category": "Movies", "difficulty": "medium", "points": 20.0, "options": ["Indiana Jones and the Last Crusade", "Stand By Me", "The River Wild", "The Thing Called Love"], "correctOption": 1}, {"question": "In Into the Wild, which real-life figure does Emile Hirsch portray, who abandons his possessions and embarks on a journey across America to live in the Alaskan wilderness?", "category": "Movies", "difficulty": "medium", "points": 20.0, "options": ["Christopher McCandless", "Jack Kerouac", "John Muir", "Henry David Thoreau"], "correctOption": 0}, {"question": "Which novel by Jack Kerouac is considered a defining work of the Beat Generation, chronicling a series of spontaneous road trips across the United States?", "category": "Literature", "difficulty": "medium", "points": 20.0, "options": ["Big Sur", "On the Road", "The Dharma Bums", "Visions of Cody"], "correctOption": 1}, {"question": "Which philosophical theme is central to Thoreau's Walden, emphasizing self-reliance and individualism in the face of societal pressures?", "category": "Philosophy", "difficulty": "hard", "points": 30.0, "options": ["Romanticism", "Transcendentalism", "Naturalism", "Realism"], "correctOption": 1}, {"question": "Which novel by William Burroughs is considered a landmark work of the Beat Generation, known for its experimental narrative style and themes of addiction and control?", "category": "Literature", "difficulty": "medium", "points": 20.0, "options": ["Soft Machine", "On the Road", "Junk", "Naked Lunch"], "correctOption": 3}, {"question": "Which of the following bands is most closely associated with the Canterbury Scene, known for its blend of progressive rock and jazz influences?", "category": "Music", "difficulty": "hard", "points": 30.0, "options": ["Soft Machine", "King Crimson", "Yes", "Genesis"], "correctOption": 0}, {"question": "Which band is considered the pioneer of the Zeuhl genre, known for its blend of progressive rock, jazz, and a unique rhythmic style, often characterized by repetitive basslines and choral vocals?", "category": "Music", "difficulty": "hard", "points": 30.0, "options": ["Magma", "Univers Zero", "Heldon", "Gong"], "correctOption": 0}, {"question": "In Frank Zappa's 1970 album Burnt Weeny Sandwich, which track is notable for its jazz influences and features a prominent guitar solo by Zappa?", "category": "Music", "difficulty": "hard", "points": 30.0, "options": ["Bobby Brown", "The Little House I Used to Live In", "The Gumbo Variations", "Peaches en Regalia\""], "correctOption": 1}, {"question": "Which Free song, released in 1970, became one of the band's most famous tracks and is known for its powerful vocals by Paul Rodgers and its iconic guitar riff?", "category": "Music", "difficulty": "medium", "points": 20.0, "options": ["All Right Now", "Fire and Water", "Wishing Well", "Heavy Load"], "correctOption": 0}, {"question": "Which Zucchero song, released in 1987, features a blend of blues and rock influences and is one of his most successful hits, often performed in both Italian and English?", "category": "Music", "difficulty": "medium", "points": 20.0, "options": ["Diamante\"", "Baila (Sexy Thing)", "Senza una Donna", "Il Volo"], "correctOption": 2}, {"question": "Which Talking Heads song, released in 1980 and featured on the album Remain in Light, is known for its Afrobeat-inspired rhythms and became one of the band's signature tracks?", "category": "Music", "difficulty": "medium", "points": 20.0, "options": ["Burning Down the House", "Psycho Killer", "Once in a Lifetime", "Life During Wartime"], "correctOption": 2}, {"question": "Which piece by Claude Debussy, inspired by a poem by Stéphane Mallarmé, is considered a turning point in modern music for its use of impressionistic harmonies and orchestration?", "category": "Music", "difficulty": "hard", "points": 30.0, "options": ["Prélude à l'après-midi d'un faune", "La Mer", "Images", "Clair de Lune"], "correctOption": 0}]}
